Joannis Linardos

Contact details

Email: me@ioannislinardos.com
Phone number: +31 617310845
Website: ioannislinardos.com

LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/ioannis-linardos

Visa status: EU national (sponsorship required in the UK)

Personal Profile

I am a conscientious and action-oriented Data Scientist with a background in Computer Science and Applied Mathematics. I am looking for an entry-level position or paid internship as a data scientist, data analyst or machine learning practitioner. I have a passion for making sense of data and extracting the value hidden in them. I have approximately two years of experience in academic and industrial projects, specializing in machine learning, statistics, operations research and data management. I also followed courses in philosophy, psychology and management.

Education

09.2019-11.2021: University of Twente, MSc, Applied Mathematics

- Specialization in Mathematics of Data Science
- Followed courses in Machine Learning, Deep Learning, Reinforcement Learning, Statistics, Big Data, Network Science, Operations Research
- Followed Honours Programme: "Change Leaders Track" (a curriculum focused on personal development, leadership skills and change management)
- GPA: 8.3/10 (master thesis pending)

09.2016-07.2019: University of Twente, BSc, Computer Science and Applied Mathematics (double degree)

- GPA: 8.1/10 (Cum Laude)
- Followed Honours Programme: "Philosophy Track"

09.2012-06.2015: National Technical University of Athens, Greece, Mechanical Engineering (withdrew)

- GPA: 8.6/10
- Distinction for performance in mathematics

Work Experience

09.2018-Present: University of Twente, Enschede, The Netherlands

- Teaching Assistant in:
 - o BSc level Mathematics (Calculus, Linear Algebra, Probability Theory, Statistics)
 - o Python programming
- Assisted and occasionally given lectures and participated in grading process of projects and exams

09.2020-12.2020: Sioux Technologies, Eindhoven, The Netherlands

- Research internship focused on Time Series Analysis with Deep Learning
- Implemented a deep learning framework for signal quality assessment on fetal heart rate data
- Framed the problem as anomaly detection using autoencoders and Generative Adversarial Networks
- Used TensorFlow/Keras, NumPy, SciPy and scikit-learn
- Contacted with external customers and incorporated their requirements
- Grade: 8.5/10

02.2019-05.2019: Hospital Group Twente, Hengelo, The Netherlands

- University-industry collaboration
- Built interactive web platform as an annotation tool to facilitate medical reporting
- Integrated Natural Language Processing tool for automatic annotation
- Communicated with end-users and integrated requirements
- Used Java and SQL for the back-end and JavaScript for the front-end

06.2015-09.2015: Aluminum of Greece, Paralia Distomou, Greece

- Engineering internship
- Data entry and data wrangling/cleaning
- Used spreadsheet and office software (primarily MS Excel)

09.2011-06.2012: Hellenic Army, Cyprus

- Served in Special Operation Forces
- Promoted to non-commissioned officer (corporal)
- Led squad of 20 privates on daily chores

Other Projects

03.2021-Present: Master Thesis: "Effects of Behaviour Adaptation on the Spread of Infectious Disease on Networks with Community Structures"

- Simulating the spread of infectious disease (digital twin)
- Research on the effects of network structure on disease spread using Graph Theory
- Stochastic modelling of the development of the dynamic system in time using systems of differential equations

11.2019-01.2020: Twitter Reaction on the Moscow Protests 2019

- Scrapped Twitter data from the web related to the Moscow protests and conducted quantitative and qualitative analysis (i.e. sentiment analysis)
- Examined the correlation between tweets and event attendance
- Big data wrangling and analysis using Apache Spark

11.2019-01.2020: Style Transfer via CycleGAN

- Used Generative Adversarial Networks to achieve emoji style transfer
- Programmed in PyTorch

02.2019-06.2019: Bachelor Thesis: "Multiscale Convolutions for Neural Networks"

- Built Convolutional Neural Networks for audio classification using TensorFlow/Keras
- Developed methods to scale the trained networks so that they can be used with higher and lower resolution recordings
- Grade: 8/10

Computer Skills

- Experienced in: Python, SQL, Java, Linux systems
- Exposure in: R, Spark, Hadoop, MATLAB, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, C, C++

Languages

Greek (native) – English (fluent) – French (intermediate) – Dutch (beginner)

Voluntary Work

05.2019-11.2020: T.S.V. Pro Deo (student improvisation theatre association), Enschede, The Netherlands

- Executive board member (secretary)
- Responsible for the flow and storage of information in the association
- Implemented change intervention by adapting improvisation theatre and social activities during the COVID-19 pandemic

11.2018-01.2019: WINS Foundation, Bali, Indonesia

- Taught English, computer skills and elementary mathematics on elementary and secondary school students
- Conducted research on the motivations of volunteers